rms.com 2019-05-01

# Legal – Risk Management Solutions - RMS

#### Privacy Policy for [rms.com](http://www.rms.com/) Website

Last Updated: February 27, 2019 

Risk Management Solutions, Inc. ( **"RMS", "we", "our", "us"** ) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We are a California corporation, with our principal office located at 7575 Gateway Boulevard, Suite 300, Newark, California 94560. This policy applies to [www.rms.com](http://www.rms.com/) and other websites ("Websites") owned and operated by RMS, and to the online services ("Services") available to our customers through certain restricted portions of our Websites. 

If you are an RMS customer, you may have access to software or functions in restricted areas of our Websites that permit you to input information regarding your clients or insureds. The treatment of such information is governed by your (or your employer's) agreement with RMS permitting you to use the applicable software or functions. In addition to the terms of any agreement, it is your responsibility to ensure that you have the authority to input such information and that you are doing so in accordance with your (or your employer's) agreement with RMS and any applicable laws and regulations, including privacy and data protection laws and regulations. 

Your use of our Websites and the Services is also subject to the _Terms of Use_. 

**Personal Data:**

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), we act as a "Processor" for the Services we provide. We function as a “Controller” when we send marketing materials or communications to potential or existing clients ("Marketing Activities") in accordance with applicable law. 

When you visit an RMS Website or use our Services, we may collect Personal Data as described below. "Personal Data" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. 

In some cases, we will ask for your consent so that we may process your Personal Data. For example, we will request your consent before we collect your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes. 

However, in other circumstances, data protection laws allow us to process your Personal Data without needing to obtain your consent. For example, we might process your Personal Data: 

  * **To perform our contract obligations  **to you and your employees on whose behalf you have obtained the necessary consents, including providing you with our Services, fulfilling orders or requests you have made, contacting you in relation to any issues with your orders or use of our Services, or where we need to provide your Personal Data to our service providers related to the provision of the Services.
  * **To comply with legal obligations** , including laws, regulations, court orders or other legal processes
  * **To pursue a legitimate interest** , except where such interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms which require protection of Personal Data. Legitimate interests may include: 
    * To communicate with you regarding the Website or Services, including to provide you with important notices regarding changes to our operations and to address and respond to your requests, inquiries, and complaints.
    * To assist in the investigation of suspected illegal or wrongful activity, and to protect and defend our rights and property, or the rights or safety of third parties.
    * To develop, provide, and improve our Services.
    * To enforce our Terms of Use, license agreements, or this Privacy Notice, or agreements with third parties.

###  1\. WHAT TYPES OF INFORMATION DOES RMS RECEIVE?

RMS receives Personal Data from you when you visit our Websites and Services. This might include information such as your name, e-mail address, or telephone number that you submit to us via our “Contact Us” function, and other information that we automatically collect when you visit our Websites and use our Services, as described below. The information you provide to RMS may include the following: 

  * Your login ID when you access and use the client area of a Website limited to registered users (the “Services”);
  * First and last name, email address, job title, phone number, company name, country and your specific questions or comments when you: 
    * register for a RMS event, such as our client conference
    * contact us to learn more about our products and services 
    * ask us a question or send feedback using RMS contact information available on a Website
    * provide feedback or reply to a blog post
    * when our Website directs you to a third party's website to complete a transaction, such as a website that processes your registration and credit card information for an RMS event.
  * First and last name, email address, resume or cv, phone number, location, referral source and any information provided in your cover letter and LinkedIn profile when you apply for a job via the "Careers" section of the Website; or

When you visit our Websites or use our Services, we also automatically collect and store certain information, including your browser type your IP address or device ID, operating system, the pages you access on the Websites or Services, the time spent on those pages, access dates and times, location data, and the page you visited before coming to our site. We use this information to monitor, analyze and administer the Websites and Services, and to better tailor them to your needs. 

**Cookies**  
To collect information this information, we use cookies. A cookie is a small data text file which a website stores on your computer's hard drive, if permitted by your web browser. A cookie can later be retrieved to identify you to us. We use cookies for the limited purposes of enhancing your visit to our Website and to enable us to track usage so that we can improve the Website and our offerings to you. 

**Pixel Tags**  
A pixel tag (also known as a "clear GIF" or "web beacon") is a tiny image – typically just one-pixel – that can be placed on a web page or in an email to you, to tell us when you have displayed that page or opened that email. 

We use third parties to collect, track and analyze this information and statistical information from users, such as the user's browser type, operating system, browsing behavior and demographic information. 

A list of companies that use cookies on our Websites is included in our Cookie Policy. The list includes a description of what services third parties perform on our Websites, the types of data they collect, and a link to applicable privacy documents from those parties. You should note, however, that the parties listed in our Cookie Policy may also dynamically redirect to other third parties, not listed in our Cookie Policy, for purposes such as interest-based advertising. 

In addition, when you use the Internet, third parties such as web analytics companies and social networking platforms may collect information about your online activities over time and across ours and other websites. This information may be used to provide advertisements for products and services that may interest you, and those companies may use cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies. 

Most browsers have settings that allow you to block certain types of cookies and also allow you to delete cookies. To learn more about browser cookies, including how to manage or delete them, look in the "Tools", "Help", "Settings", "Internet Options" or similar section of your web browser. 

For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, or to opt out of certain tracking, visit the NAI’s consumer website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. If you choose to opt out using these tools, you need to opt out separately for each of your devices and for each web browser (such as Internet Explorer, Firefox or Safari) that you use on each device. 

###  2\. DO NOT TRACK

Some web browsers give the ability to prevent tracking of your online activity by setting a preference in your browser alerting websites you visit that you do not want them to track your online activities. This is referred to as a Do Not Track ("DNT") signal. This is different than blocking or deleting cookies, as browsers with an enabled DNT Signal may still accept cookies. 

Please note that our Websites and Services may not recognize or take action in response to DNT signals from your browser. 

###  3\. HOW DO WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?

In general, we use your Personal Data to complete the transaction that you have requested from us. For example, we will use your Personal Information to: 

  * Deliver, maintain, monitor, protect and assess our Websites and Services and to enhance your experience 
  * Communicate with you in response to your requests;
  * Establish or verify your identity when you register for the Services;
  * Respond to you about your job application;
  * Register you for an event which you have selected;
  * Address the question or feedback which you have sent to us; and
  * Enforce our Website and Services Terms of Use.

###  4\. WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE THE PERSONAL DATA WE RECEIVE ABOUT YOU?

RMS does not sell your Personal Data to anyone. Nor do we provide your Personal Data to non-RMS parties to market non-RMS products to you. RMS will share your Personal Data with the following categories of recipients: 

  * RMS employees, contractors and consultants (including employees, contractors and consultants of RMS subsidiaries and affiliated companies), in the United States, the European Economic Area (EEA) and India, who have a need to know your Personal Data to provide RMS services and information to you;
  * Our third-party vendors, consultants and other service providers who assist RMS with the operation of the Websites and Services when they require access to such information to provide the services for us. This may include cloud computing companies, cloud communication platform as a service (PaaS), web analytics services, employment-related service providers, social networking services and mailing and emailing services. For example, we may use a third party to process submissions of resumes and CVs through the RMS Careers section of the Website; 
  * Trusted non-RMS parties who assist RMS with providing RMS Services and information to you, such as CVent and Marketo, who help us with RMS event registration and processing of your payments;
  * Trusted non-RMS parties that provide customer relationship management applications such as [Salesforce.com](https://www.salesforce.com/); and
  * Trusted non-RMS parties such as hosting, analytics and search engine providers such as Google Analytics that assist us in the improvement and optimization of the Website and who may have access to your Personal Data.

When you submit a comment on one of our blog posts, your comments and any personal information that you include in that comment will be shared with other visitors to that Website. 

RMS will also disclose your Personal Data if we are required to do so by law, to enforce our Terms of Use, or in urgent circumstances to protect personal safety, the public, or our Website, as permitted by law or as otherwise required by law. 

We will also disclose your Personal Data to third parties in the event that we sell any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your data to the prospective buyer of such business or assets or if we sell all or substantially all of our assets or are acquired by a third party, in which case information held by us about our users will be one of the transferred assets, however it will remain protected in accordance with this privacy policy. 

###  5\. WHERE DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

If you are located outside of the United States, you should be aware that the Websites and Services are hosted in the United States, and your information will be transferred to, processed and stored in the United States, the EEA and Australia. It may also be processed by staff operating outside of your country, who work for us or one of our third party service providers. 

Wherever the data is, it will be treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable privacy laws in North America and the EU. These laws may be different from the privacy laws in your country, and may not always provide the same level of protection for your information. However, that does not change our commitment to safeguard your privacy, and we will comply with all applicable laws related to the cross-border data disclosure of your personal information. Where required to transfer your Personal Data within the RMS group and to our partners we will implement binding corporate rules and Standard Contractual Clauses. A copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses may be obtained on your request by emailing us at [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com). 

###  6\. HOW DOES RMS PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

RMS protects your Personal Data by maintaining commercially reasonable, industry standard physical, electronic and procedural safeguards. For example, we use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption. In addition, we only allow employees to access Personal Data only when required to fulfill their job responsibilities. The Internet, however, is not perfectly secure, and we are not responsible for security incidents not reasonably foreseeable or reasonably within our control.

###  7\. HOW LONG DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We will retain your Personal Data for as long as necessary to provide access to the Websites and Services to you or as long as legally permissible in accordance with applicable law, including as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, as well as to comply with applicable industry standards, and in accordance with disaster recovery procedures. As such, retention periods vary depending on the type of Personal Data and how it is used. For example, if you contact us via email we will keep your data for three years after such contact; and we will also retain the information we automatically collect when you visit our Website and Services for three years.

###  8\. YOUR RIGHTS

In certain circumstances, when we are acting as a controller, you have rights related to the Personal Data we hold about you. Below is an outline of those rights and how to exercise those rights. Please note that we will require you to provide adequate proof of your identity before responding to any requests to exercise your rights. To exercise any of your rights, please email [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com). Please note that for each of the rights below we may have valid legal reasons to refuse your request. In such instances we will let you know if that is the case. In addition, the rules in your country may provide you with additional rights or may limit the rights noted below. In all cases, we will comply with the applicable laws.

  * **Access** : You may have the right to know whether we process Personal Data about you, and if we do, to access data we hold about you and certain information about how we use it and who we share it with.
  * **Correction** : You may have the right to require us to correct any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate and have incomplete data completed.
  * **Erasure** : Under certain circumstances, you may have the right to request that we erase the Personal Data we hold about you.
  * **Restriction of Processing to Storage Only** : Under certain circumstances, you may have a right to require us to stop processing the Personal Data we hold about you other than for storage purposes.
  * **Objection to Processing** : Under certain circumstances, you may have the right to object to our processing of data about you on grounds related to your particular situation, and we can be required to no longer process your Personal Data. 
  * **Withdrawal of Consent** : Where you have provided your consent to us processing your Personal Data, you can withdraw your consent at any time by emailing [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com). 
  * **Objection to Marketing** : At any time you have the right to object to our processing of data about you in order to send you promotions, special offers and other marketing materials, including where we build profiles for such purposes, and we will stop processing the data for that purpose. You can object to processing of your data for marketing purposes at any time by emailing [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com).

###  9\. SOCIAL MEDIA FEATURES AND WIDGETS

Our Websites includes social media features and widgets which allow you to share articles from our websites. These features are usually recognizable by their third party brand or logo and may collect your IP address, and set a cookie to enable the feature to work properly. These social media features and widgets may provide information to their associated social networks or third parties about your interactions with our web pages that you visit, even if you did not click on or otherwise interact with the social media feature or widget. Information is transmitted from your browser and may include an identifier assigned by the social network or third party, information about your browser type, operating system, device type, IP address and the URL of the web page where the feature appears. These social media features and widgets are hosted by social media companies that have their own privacy policies and we encourage you to read them. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

###  10\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT RMS ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

Please contact us at [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com) with any questions about this Privacy Policy, for information about how to exercise your rights in relation to this privacy policy, for information about the balancing test that we use to consider data use for our legitimate interests or for the following: 

Opting Out of Communications: From time to time you will receive an e-mail or other communication from us regarding RMS products, services or information which we believe to be of interest to you. If you are not interested in receiving this information, you may follow the instructions in the communication explaining how you may be removed from our distribution list. Alternatively, or if there are no instructions in the communication, you may send an e-mail to [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com) requesting removal from our distribution list. We will endeavor to take prompt action to process your request. 

**Complaints** : In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how we process your Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com) and we will endeavor to deal with your request as soon as possible. This is without prejudice to your right to raise a complaint with the data protection supervisory authority in the EU country in which you live or work where you think we have infringed data protection laws. 

**California Residents** : If you are a resident of California, you may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal data (if any) for marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at [privacy@rms.com](mailto:mailto:privacy@rms.com)

###  11\. WILL THIS PRIVACY POLICY CHANGE?

RMS reserves the right to modify, amend, add to, replace or remove this Privacy Policy at any time. When we do, we will post a notice in the Websites or Services, or otherwise as required by law. Should we make material changes impacting the Services, we will notify our client contact of record and obtain any consents required under applicable law. Unless otherwise noted, changes to this privacy policy will be effective when posted. You are advised to check the Privacy, Terms of Use and Legal links on the Website for updates whenever you visit the Website. 

Risk Management Solutions, Inc. ("RMS") provides this website to you subject to these Terms of Use. By using this website, you accept and agree to comply with these Terms of Use. If you do not agree to these Terms of Use, do not use this website. 

###  1\. Ownership

This website, including any and all content, text, data, information and images ("Content"), and any copyrights, trademarks, patents, trade secrets or other intellectual property rights in such Content ("Intellectual Property Rights"), is the property of RMS or its licensors. You may not use any Content of this website unless specifically permitted by the Content or these Terms of Use. 

ALM, Exceedance, RiskBrowser, RiskLink, RiskOnline, RiskSearch, RiskTools, the RMS logo, RMS, RMS (one) are registered trademarks of Risk Management Solutions, Inc. 

All other trademarks are the property of their respective owners. 

###  2\. Use of this Website

This website includes pages that are publicly available to all users ("General Website"), and a restricted area that is only available to users to whom RMS has specifically permitted access ("Registered User Site"). 

In general, you may only use the General Website for your personal, informational, and non-commercial use, without modification or alteration of this website in any way. 

Your use of the Registered User Site is subject to (i) the terms and conditions of your (or your employer's) agreement with RMS regarding use of the Registered User Site, if applicable; and (ii) any terms and conditions, restrictions and license agreements set forth in the Registered User Site with respect to the Content. You should presume that all Content in the Registered User Site is confidential and proprietary to RMS, and that you may not reproduce, copy, sell, publish, distribute, modify or display such Content unless specifically permitted in writing by RMS. 

You agree not to remove or modify any copyright or other proprietary notices contained in this website. 

###  3\. User Content

Except as provided in the Privacy Policy, or in a written agreement that you or your employer has with RMS, any Content that you submit to RMS using this website or in connection with this website ("User Content") will be deemed non-confidential and RMS may disclose it to any party without your permission. You agree that, except as provided in the [Privacy Policy] or in a written agreement with RMS, you grant to RMS a worldwide, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, sublicenseable, non-exclusive right and license to translate, reproduce, sell, publish, distribute, modify, adapt, display, perform, promote, link to or use, in any form or media, any User Content. RMS is not obligated to use or post any Content you submit, and makes no representations or warranties regarding any User Content on this website. 

You agree not to submit to RMS or this website any User Content that you are not authorized to submit, and that User Content does not and will not infringe upon any other party's Intellectual Property Rights. RMS undertakes no obligation to verify your right to use User Content or submit it to this website. 

###  4\. Registration and Passwords

Your access to the Registered User Site may require a user name and password ("User Login"). Any details you provide to us to establish or use your User Login must be correct, current and complete. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your User Login, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your User Login. You agree to notify us immediately, at [info@rms.com](mailto:info@rms.com), of any loss, theft or unauthorized use of your User Login. RMS reserves the right to modify, revoke or refuse a User Login to you or any other party. In addition, RMS reserves the right to make some, all, or none of its website a Registered User Site. 

If you receive access to the Registered User Site through your employer without the necessity of a User Login, you must still comply with these Terms of Use. 

###  5\. Software

Any software that RMS makes available for download from this website is the copyrighted work of RMS or its licensors. Your use of downloadable software is subject to the terms and conditions of the End User License Agreement ("EULA") applicable to the software, or the applicable written agreement between you (or your employer) and RMS regarding the software. Any other use is expressly prohibited by RMS. By downloading software from RMS' website, you also agree that you will not download, use or transmit any software in violation of any export control laws and regulations, including but not limited to U.S. and European export control laws and regulations. 

###  6\. Linking

You agreed to give us prior written notice, to [info@rms.com](mailto:info@rms.com), if you wish to link any other web page to this website. Only a direct link to the home page may be made, without framing. We reserve complete discretion to refuse anyone permission to link to our website. 

###  7\. Prohibited Content and Conduct

You agree that you will submit User Content only as permitted by this website and these Terms of Use. You will NOT (i) submit User Content that is not functionally and technically compatible with this website; (ii) attempt to and will not damage, corrupt, tamper with or infect this website, Content or any telecommunication system of RMS with a virus or other malicious computer program; (iii) send, create or reply to "mailbombs," engage in "spamming" or undertake any other activity that may adversely affect the use, functionality or enjoyment of this website by anyone; or (iv) compromise the security of this website, or anyone's User Login or account. 

Furthermore, you agree that you will not engage in any conduct in connection with this website, (including the submission of User Content) that: 

  * **+** is illegal, misappropriated, infringing or dilutive;
  * **+** is inaccurate or misleading;
  * **+** is defamatory, libelous or in violation of anyone's privacy rights;
  * **+** is threatening or harassing;
  * **+** is obscene, offensive or otherwise inappropriate; or
  * **+** you do not have a right to engage in, including but not limited to providing inside information; or providing information that you are prohibited from disclosing because of your obligations to a current or former employer, or your obligations under a non-disclosure agreement with another party.

RMS may or may not elect to pre-screen, monitor, or edit any User Content posted in chat rooms, message boards, blogs and the like which may be available through this website. However, RMS has the sole and exclusive discretion to remove any User Content that, in RMS' judgment, fails to comply with these Terms of Use or the law, or is otherwise objectionable. RMS is not responsible for any failure or delay in removing such User Content. 

You agree that if you engage in any behavior that violates these Terms of Use, RMS may release your details to system administrators of other websites and law enforcement to assist them in resolving such incidents of misconduct. You also agree to cooperate with RMS if RMS suspects that you or another party has breached these Terms of Use or laws applicable to this website. 

###  8\. Third Party Websites and Information

RMS has no obligation to monitor, control or restrict the use of this website, or any third party websites available via links to this website. RMS is not responsible for the content, accuracy, compliance with laws or any other aspects of non-RMS websites. The inclusion of a link on RMS' website does not imply any endorsement, evaluation or verification of the linked site by RMS. Furthermore, RMS does not have any obligation to verify any User Content submitted by a user or to provide you with any information regarding any Content, User Content, third party (including third party websites, links or content) or user. 

###  9\. Disclaimers

THIS WEBSITE, INCLUDING ANY CONTENT, LINKS, AND SOFTWARE PROVIDED IN CONNECTION WITH THIS WEBSITE ("ASSOCIATED MATERIALS"), ARE PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS. RMS DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THIS WEBSITE AND ASSOCIATED MATERIALS, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, RESULTS, ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS, ACCESSIBILITY, COMPATIBILITY, SECURITY AND FREEDOM FROM COMPUTER VIRUSES. IF APPLICABLE LAW DOES NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF ANY OF THE ABOVE WARRANTIES, THE REMAINING EXCLUSIONS WILL APPLY TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW. 

###  10\. Limitation of Liability and Indemnification

RMS SHALL HAVE NO LIABILITY TO YOU, UNDER ANY CONTRACT, TORT, STRICT LIABILITY OR OTHER LEGAL THEORY, FOR ANY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND RELATING TO YOUR USE OR INABILITY TO USE THIS WEBSITE, ITS CONTENT, LINKS AND SOFTWARE, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOST PROFITS, LOSS OF DATA, LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF GOODWILL, INTERRUPTION OF WORK OR COMPUTER OR SYSTEM FAILURE), EVEN IF RMS HAS BEEN INFORMED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. 

YOU AGREE TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND AND HOLD HARMLESS RMS, INCLUDING ITS PARENT, SUBSIDIARY AND AFFILIATED COMPANIES, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES AND AGENTS OF THE FOREGOING, FROM ANY AND ALL DEMANDS, CLAIMS, ACTIONS, DAMAGES, LIABILITIES, EXPENSES OR HARMS, INCLUDING ATTORNEYS FEES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE OF THIS WEBSITE. 

###  11\. Dispute Resolution, Choice of Law, Etc.

All disputes relating to this website and your use of this website, including but not limited to breaches of these Terms of Use and the Privacy Policy, shall be governed by the laws of California without giving effect to any law or rule that would cause the laws of any other jurisdiction to be applied. You consent to the exclusive jurisdiction of and venue in the State and Federal courts of Santa Clara County, California, and agree that venue in such courts is appropriate. 

If a court of competent jurisdiction finds that any provision of these Terms of Use or the Privacy Policy is invalid or unenforceable, such provision will be deemed stricken without effect on the remaining provisions, which shall remain in full force and effect. 

###  12\. Modification or Termination

RMS may, in its complete discretion, modify, edit, translate, suspend, restrict access to or terminate this website, Content or any link at any time without liability or prior notice. RMS may also, in its complete discretion, terminate any party's right or access to this website. 

These Terms of Use were last updated on May 29, 2008. RMS reserves the right to modify, amend, add to, replace or remove these Terms of Use at any time. You are advised to check the Terms of Use and Privacy links for updates whenever you visit the RMS website. 

###  13\. Contacting RMS

If you have an inquiry regarding this website, including a report of any behavior in connection with this website that violates these Terms of use or applicable laws, please contact us at [info@rms.com](mailto:info@rms.com). You may also contact us via mail at: 

Risk Management Solutions, Inc.  
Attn: General Counsel  
7575 Gateway Blvd.  
Newark, CA 94560 

This Cookie Notice describes how Risk Management Solutions, Inc. ( **"we"** or **"us"** ) use cookies and similar technologies to collect and store information when you visit our website. For additional information on our data processing activities, please visit our Privacy Policy, available here. 

###  What are Cookies and what information do they collect?

Like most companies, we automatically collect and store certain information from visitors to our website. This may include your browser type, your IP address or device ID, operating system, the pages you access on the website or services, the time spent on those pages, access dates and times, location data, and the page you visited before coming to our website. We use this information to monitor, analyze and administer the website and services, and to better tailor them to your needs.

To collect this information, we use a variety of technological tools including cookies and pixel tags. A cookie is a small data text file which a website stores on your computer’s hard drive, if permitted by your browser. A cookie can later be retrieved to identify you. We use cookies for the limited purposes of enhancing your visit to our Website and to enable us to track usage so that we can improve the website and our offerings to you. Cookies are common and used on a number of websites. Each cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie and usually the IP address or another unique number of the device, and thus may contain Personal Information.

A pixel tag (also known as a “clear GIF” or “web beacon”) is a tiny image – typically just one-pixel – that can be placed on a web page or in an email to you, to tell us when you have displayed that page or opened that email.

###  Session and Persistent Cookies

Our website may place session and persistent cookies on your device. The difference between a session and a persistent cookie relates to the length of time the cookie lasts. Session cookies are cookies that typically last for as long as you are using your browser, or browser session. When you end your browser session, the cookie expires. Persistent cookies, as the name implies, are persistent and will last after you close your browser. This allows, for example, for quicker and often more convenient access to our website.

###  Types of Cookies, purpose of Cookies and Legal Basis for Cookies?

There are different types of cookies:

  * Strictly necessary cookies: Strictly necessary cookies are required to browse the website and use the functionalities of the website. If you disable necessary cookies, the functionality of the website will be affected. The legal basis for the collection of information through the use of strictly necessary cookies is contract performance (if we concluded a contract on the use of the website with you) or legitimate interests of us or third parties, such as the provision of a functioning website. More information on the balancing test is available upon request.
  * Functionality cookies: Functionality cookies enable us to store the selections and settings made by you (e.g. language, region, account preferences). If you disable functionality cookies the functionality of the website may be affected. The legal basis for the collection of information through functionality cookies is your consent.
  * Analytics and targeting/advertising cookies: Analytics cookies allow us to collect information on the use and scope of the website by individual users. This includes whether a user has visited the website previously, the website the user comes from, the overall site usage and areas that users prefer and thus allows us to improve the performance of the website and the user’s experience in using that website. These cookies also allow us to analyze the efficiency of our marketing activities. Targeting/advertisement cookies allow us to do the same, and also to provide targeted advertisement tailored for your interests. If you disable such cookies you will not receive a customized website experience or targeted advertising. The legal basis for the collection of such information by analytics and targeting/advertisement cookies is your consent.

###  First Party and Third Party Cookies

Our websites may place first party cookies and allow third parties to place cookies on your device. The difference between a first party cookie and a third party cookie relates to the control of the party who serves the cookie. First party cookies are cookies that are specific to the website that created them. Their use enables us to operate an efficient service and to track the patterns of behavior of visitors to the website. Third party cookies, on the other hand, are placed on your device by a third party (i.e., not by us). While we may allow third parties to access the website to place these cookies on users’ devices, we do not retain control over the information supplied by the cookies, nor do we retain access to that data. This information is controlled wholly by that third party and subject to their privacy notice. The legal basis for the collection of information through third party cookies depends on the type of cookie, please see below.

###  Cookies used on RMS.com

The following table lists the cookies that we use on our website. 

Name  | Source  | File  | Purpose  | Life Span  | Cookie Type   
---|---|---|---|---|---  
RMS  |  | refcookie  | Used for storm page, storm page displayed based on cookies value  | 30 minutes  | First party, Strictly necessary cookies   
DoubleClick  | stats.g.doubleclick.net  | Channel ID  | DoubleClick cookie is used to enable remarketing—for products like AdWords on the Google Display Network. If you enable this feature, information—including the third-party DoubleClick cookie—is sent to the Analytics servers  | 2 years  | Third party   
Facebook Connect  | fbevents.js  | fr  | In connection with the web services and APIs provided by Facebook Pixel to track custom audience and conversion events.  | 3 month  | Third party   
Google Analytics  | analytics.js  | _ga  | This cookie name is asssociated with Google Universal Analytics - which is a significant update to Google's more commonly used analytics service. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier  | 2 year  | Third party   
_gid  | This cookie name is asssociated with Google Universal Analytics.It appears to store and update a unique value for each page visited.  | 24 hours  | Third party   
_gat_UA-22492098-1  | This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.  | Session  | Third Party   
_gat_UA-22492098-14  | This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.  | Session  | Third party   
_gat_UA-22492098-16  | This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.  | Sesssion  | Third party   
_gat  | This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics, according to documentation it is used to throttle the request rate - limiting the collection of data on high traffic sites.  | 10 minutes  | Third party   
Google Tag Manager  | googletagmanager.com  | gtm.js  | It enables Tag Manager to fire tags by inserting gtm.js into the page (or through the use of an iframe when JavaScript isn't available).  | \-  | Third party   
LinkedIn Ads  | px.ads.linkedin.com  | BIzoID  | LinkedIn's marketing services that enable website owners to gain insight into types of users on their site based on LinkedIn profile data.  | 1 month  | Third party   
UserMatchHistory  | 1 month  | Third party   
lang  | Session  | Third party   
Marketo  | munchkin.js  | _mkto_trk  | This cookie is set by Marketo. This allows a website to track visitor behavior on the sites on which the cookie is installed and to link a visitor to the recipient of an email marketing campaign, to measure campaign effectiveness. Tracking is performed anonymously until a user identifies himself by submitting a form.  | 2 years  | Third party   
forms2.rms.com  |  | _cfduid  | Cookie assoiated with sites using CloudFlare, used to speed up page load times. According to CloudFlare it is used to override any security restrictions based on the IP address the visitor is coming from. It does not contain any user identification information.  | 1 day  | Third party   
BIGipServersj10web_app_https  | \-  | Third party   
Youtube  | iframe_api  | VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  | This cookie is set by Youtube to keep track of user preferences for Youtube videos embedded in sites;it can also determine whether the website visitor is using the new or old version of the Youtube interface.  | 6 month  | Third party   
PREF  | Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites  | 8 month  | Third party   
YSC  | Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.  | Session  | Third party   
GPS  | Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.  | Session  | Third party   
  
  * Name
  * RMS
  * Source
  *   * File
  * refcookie
  * Purpose
  * Used for storm page, storm page displayed based on cookies value.
  * Life Span
  * 30 minutes
  * Cookie Type
  * First party, Strictly necessary cookies

  * Name
  * DoubleClick
  * Source
  * stats.g.doubleclick.net
  * File
  * Channel ID
  * Purpose
  * DoubleClick cookie is used to enable remarketing—for products like AdWords on the Google Display Network. If you enable this feature, information—including the third-party DoubleClick cookie—is sent to the Analytics servers
  * Life Span
  * 2 years
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Facebook Connect
  * Source
  * fbevents.js
  * File
  * fr
  * Purpose
  * In connection with the web services and APIs provided by Facebook Pixel to track custom audience and conversion events.
  * Life Span
  * 3 month
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _ga
  * Purpose
  * This cookie name is asssociated with Google Universal Analytics - which is a significant update to Google's more commonly used analytics service. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier
  * Life Span
  * 2 year
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _gid
  * Purpose
  * This cookie name is asssociated with Google Universal Analytics.It appears to store and update a unique value for each page visited.
  * Life Span
  * 24 hours
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _gat_UA-22492098-1
  * Purpose
  * This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.
  * Life Span
  * Sesssion
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _gat_UA-22492098-14
  * Purpose
  * This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.
  * Life Span
  * Sesssion
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _gat_UA-22492098-16
  * Purpose
  * This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.
  * Life Span
  * Sesssion
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Analytics
  * Source
  * analytics.js
  * File
  * _gat
  * Purpose
  * This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics, according to documentation it is used to throttle the request rate - limiting the collection of data on high traffic sites.
  * Life Span
  * 10 minutes
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Google Tag Manager
  * Source
  * googletagmanager.com
  * File
  * gtm.js
  * Purpose
  * It enables Tag Manager to fire tags by inserting gtm.js into the page (or through the use of an iframe when JavaScript isn't available).
  * Life Span
  * -
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * LinkedIn Ads
  * Source
  * px.ads.linkedin.com
  * File
  * BIzoID
  * Purpose
  * LinkedIn's marketing services that enable website owners to gain insight into types of users on their site based on LinkedIn profile data.
  * Life Span
  * 1 month
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * LinkedIn Ads
  * Source
  * px.ads.linkedin.com
  * File
  * UserMatchHistory
  * Purpose
  * LinkedIn's marketing services that enable website owners to gain insight into types of users on their site based on LinkedIn profile data.
  * Life Span
  * 1 month
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * LinkedIn Ads
  * Source
  * px.ads.linkedin.com
  * File
  * lang
  * Purpose
  * LinkedIn's marketing services that enable website owners to gain insight into types of users on their site based on LinkedIn profile data.
  * Life Span
  * Session
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Marketo
  * Source
  * munchkin.js
  * File
  * _mkto_trk
  * Purpose
  * This cookie is set by Marketo. This allows a website to track visitor behavior on the sites on which the cookie is installed and to link a visitor to the recipient of an email marketing campaign, to measure campaign effectiveness. Tracking is performed anonymously until a user identifies himself by submitting a form.
  * Life Span
  * 2 years
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * forms2.rms.com
  * Source
  *   * File
  * _cfduid
  * Purpose
  * Cookie assoiated with sites using CloudFlare, used to speed up page load times. According to CloudFlare it is used to override any security restrictions based on the IP address the visitor is coming from. It does not contain any user identification information.
  * Life Span
  * 1 day
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * forms2.rms.com
  * Source
  *   * File
  * BIGipServersj10web_app_https
  * Purpose
  * Cookie assoiated with sites using CloudFlare, used to speed up page load times. According to CloudFlare it is used to override any security restrictions based on the IP address the visitor is coming from. It does not contain any user identification information.
  * Life Span
  * -
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Youtube
  * Source
  * iframe_api
  * File
  * VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
  * Purpose
  * This cookie is set by Youtube to keep track of user preferences for Youtube videos embedded in sites;it can also determine whether the website visitor is using the new or old version of the Youtube interface.
  * Life Span
  * 6 month
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Youtube
  * Source
  * iframe_api
  * File
  * PREF
  * Purpose
  * Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites
  * Life Span
  * 8 month
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Youtube
  * Source
  * iframe_api
  * File
  * YSC
  * Purpose
  * Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.
  * Life Span
  * Session
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Youtube
  * Source
  * iframe_api
  * File
  * GPS
  * Purpose
  * Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.
  * Life Span
  * Session
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

###  Cookies used on ProjectQuantum.info

The following table lists the cookies that we use on our website. 

Name | Source | File | Purpose | Life Span | Cookie Type | Opt Out  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Webflow | project-quantum.js | wf_auth | This cookie is set by Webflow to track authentication and access to view the website. | Session | Third party | For information on opting out of Webflow's cookie policy [go here](https://webflow.com/legal/cookie-policy)  
Cookie Consent | cookieconsent.js | cookieconsent_status | This cookies is set to track which users have dismissed the cookie policy banner | Session | Third party | For information on opting out of Cookie Consent's cookie policy [go here](https://cookieconsent.insites.com/download/)  
Vimeo | .vimeo.com | vuid | These cookies are set to track an embeddable video player. Vimeo considers these cookies essential to the video player experience. | Session | Third party | For information on opting out of Vimeo's cookie policy [go here](https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy).  
player  
_gid  
_gcl  
_au  
_ga  
_fbp  
  
  * Name
  * Webflow
  * Source
  * project-quantum.js
  * File
  * wf_auth
  * Purpose
  * This cookie is set by Webflow to track authentication and access to view the website.
  * Life Span
  * Session
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

  * Name
  * Cookie Consent
  * Source
  * cookieconsent.js
  * File
  * cookieconsent_status
  * Purpose
  * This cookies is set to track which users have dismissed the cookie policy banner.
  * Life Span
  * Session
  * Cookie Type
  * Third party

###  Disabling, Deleting, or Opting Out of Cookies

If you do not/no longer want to have cookies placed on your device by us or third parties, many of them offer ways to opt out. Where possible, we have provided a link in the table above that explains how to opt out.

In addition, most web browsers allow at least some control of most cookies through browser settings. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser to decline cookies. You may also delete existing cookies through your browser.

However, please note that if you disable cookies, you may not be able to use the full functionality of our websites. In particular, you may have limited access to some areas or be transitioned to a different experience.

###  Contact us

For further information on our use of cookies and similar technologies, please contact us: 

Risk Management Services, Inc.  
7575 Gateway Boulevard  
Suite 300  
Newark, California 94560 

This notice addresses AB370, amending the California Online Privacy Protection Act, which requires website operators that collect personal identifiable information about California residents to disclose: 

  * **+** how they respond to "Do Not Track" ("DNT") signals; and
  * **+** whether third parties collect personally identifiable information about users who visit the website.

###  1\. What is DNT and a DNT signal?

DNT is a mechanism allowing a user of a website to control the tracking of their use of that website. A DNT signal is a request to a web application to disable its tracking of a user of a website. 

###  2\. How does RMS respond to a DNT signal?

RMS does not track users of www.rms.com and to such an extent, RMS does not respond to DNT signals. 

###  3\. Do third parties collect personally identifiable information about users of www.rms.com?

RMS does not authorize the collection of personally identifiable information of a user for online behavioral advertising purposes while the user is logged onto www.rms.com.
